我警告过你再进赌场会有什么下场
You were told what would happen if you came back here.
上次看到你过了早上八点还穿着睡衣
The last time I saw you in your P.J.s after 8 a.m.,
大概是你四岁的时候
I think you were 4.
今天不上学
We're off today.
老师们休息
Teachers' retreat.
我不想穿衣服了
I didn't feel like getting dressed.
这与阿什利没关系吧
This wouldn't have anything to do with Ashley, would it?
我与他分手
Did I do the right thing,
做得对吗
breaking up with him?
宝贝  我不知道
Oh, sweetie. I don't know.
这个问题只有你能回答
That's something only you can answer.
太糟糕了
It sucks.
我很想他
I miss him a lot.
是啊  你一直坐在那读《傲慢与偏见》
Yeah, well, you're not doing yourself any favors,
起不了任何作用
sitting around reading "Pride And Prejudice."
只会让事情更糟
That's just gonna make it worse.
跟听阿黛勒的歌没什么区别
You might as well be listening to Adele.
她懂这种痛  简·奥斯汀也是
Hey, she totally gets it, and so does Jane Austen.
你知道自己需要什么吗
You know what you need?
新的生活
A new life?
消遣
A distraction.
而碰巧
And it just so happens,
我知道完美的后分手时代日程
I know the perfect post-breakup routine.
今晚你我要去
Tonight you and I
灰木瓜买香辣吉士热狗
go get chili-cheese dogs from Gray's Papaya.
偷偷带进安洁莉卡影院看两场电影
We smuggle them into a double feature at the Angelika.
我知道你为我好
I know you mean well,
但和老爸一起出去
but I don't think going out with my dad is going to...
不会让我好起来的
make me feel better.
那和女友们安分地待一晚上怎么样
Well, how about just a low-key evening with your girlfriends?
你们可以连续看约翰·休斯电影
You guys can have a John Hughes' marathon
做做《大都会》上的问答
and fill out a "Cosmo" quiz.
老爸  八十年代打电话来
Dad, the '80s just called.
要你还它的消遣节目
It wants its plan back.
拜托  奶奶去了城北
Come on. Gram's upstate.
去做水疗了  她不会烦你
She's doing some spa retreat. She'll be out of your hair.
我也可以消失
And I can make myself scarce.
确实有几个朋友建议搞个女孩之夜
A few of my friends have been suggesting a girls' night.
也许我该打电话约她们
Maybe I'll call 'em.
不要也许  打电话给她们
No maybe. You're going to call them,
还要玩得开开心心的
And you're going to have a great time.
如果是八十年代来电
And if that's the '80s,
就说《大都会》问答可以给他们
tell them they can have "Cosmo"...
但约翰·休斯的电影是我的
but I'm keeping John Hughes.
如果是贝克特呢
And if it's Beckett?
谢谢
Thank you.
大西洋城宝石蓝
Ooh. The Sapphire. In Atlantic City?
我喜欢那里  死者是谁
I love that place. All right. Who's our victim?
是舞女还是挥金如土的赌狂
Is it a showgirl, some big-money high roller?
不  死者是萨姆·西格尔
No, our victim is Sam Siegel,
宝石蓝的合伙人
co-owner of the Sapphire,
"在宝石蓝你永远是赢家"
where you're always a winner.
不见得吧  瞧瞧这个
Yeah, not always, by the looks of things.
死亡时间在九点到十一点之间
Guy cashed in his chips between 9:00 and 11:00.
胸口中了一颗小口径子弹
Took a small caliber to the chest.
枪口闪光烧到了他的衬衫
Muzzle flash burned his shirt at the point of entry.
凶手站得很近
The shooter was standing close.
这个距离  在扣动扳机前
Close enough to give him a bloody lip
都能给他一个血腥之吻了
before pulling the trigger.
为什么像西格尔这样的人
So what's a guy like Siegel doing in
会在晚上这个时间出现在纽约
an abandoned delivery dock in New York City
废弃的卸货码头呢
at that time of night?
一定有什么大事
Must have been something important enough
让他亲自驱车从大西洋城赶来
for him to drive down from Atlantic City.
这家伙拥有一座赌场
You know, the man owned a casino.
这种大款一般会有私人司机啊
A guy like that, you'd think he'd have a driver.
尤其他还预料到自己会有麻烦
Especially since he was expecting trouble.
他也不是没准备
He came heavy.
357口径马格南左轮手枪
It's a .357 Magnum
六发子弹还在弹巢里
with all six still asleep in the cylinder.
他甚至都没从箱子里把枪拿出来
He didn't even pull it out of the glove box.
如果拿出来了  那躺在地上的人就是对方了
If he did. We'd be standing over the other guy.
是啊  要知道何时观望  何时弃
Yeah, you gotta know when to hold 'em and know when to fold 'em.
何时放手  何时休
Know when to walk away, and know when to run.
埃斯波西托警探
Detective Esposito,
请放尊重点  这里有具死尸
a little respect, please. I mean, there is a dead body here.
我怎么了
What'd I do?
你和她分手了
You broke up with her.
那是我们共同的决定  这是有区别的
We broke up with each other. That's different.
是啊  你会以为有区别
Yeah, you'd think it'd be different,
-但并非如此  -能给他讲讲吗
- but no. - Will you tell him?
不  我说过了  这事我不插手
No, I told you. I'm staying out of this one.
伙计们
All right, guys,
打电话给宝石蓝  了解一下西格尔的背景
call the Sapphire, get some background on Siegel,
找出可能拍到案发经过的
And look for surveillance cameras
监控摄像头或者可能目击事发的保安
or security guards that might have seen something.
女人啊
Women.
你确定你要找一个共度余生吗
You sure you want to spend the rest of your life with one?
是的  我的女人喜欢我
Uh, yeah. Mine likes me.
说到大西洋城
Ooh, speaking of Atlantic City,
可是单身派对的绝佳去处
perfect place for a bachelor party.
这才像话  哥们
Ooh. That's what I'm talking about, bro.
我们可以租辆车
We could rent one of these right here,
逛逛赌场  或许去俱乐部玩玩
hit the casino, maybe the club.
而我想的是
Uh, I-I was thinking more along the lines of...
露营
camping trip.
你...
Oh, you were... Oh.
首先
Uh, first of all,
不行
no.
其次  你说了不算
Second, it's not up to you.
单身派对是伴郎说了算
The bachelor party is strictly best man territory.
顺便说一句  你大喜的日子还有多久
And by the way, your big date is what,
就两个月了吧
like two months away?
你得正式向伴郎发出邀请了
So you need to officially tell the guy
好让他开始筹划
so that he can start planning something.
还有时间
I still got some time.
我去查查监控摄像头的事
Um, I-I'm gonna go check on those cameras.
他妈...
What the...
瞧见了没
Did you see that?
他回避我
He just sidestepped me.
怎么回事
What's that about?
好像一想到婚期将至
It's almost as though the thought of marriage
就让他感觉末日来临
fills him with an impending sense of doom.
不  那是我
Oh, no, wait. That's me.
有导航系统
Nav system?
对  看来西格尔来这前
Yeah, and it looks like Siegel made a stop
还去过另一处
just before he got here.
西区大街537号
537 West End Avenue.
看来萨姆在曼哈顿有旧交
Looks like Sam's got a friend here in Manhattan.
萨姆·西格尔  46岁
Sam Siegel, 46 years old,
是靠房地产发家的
got his start in real estate development,
然后在1999年创立
and then he went on to launch
宝石蓝海滨度假胜地和赌场
The Sapphire Coast Resort and Casino in 1999.
要做一个赌场主必会与人树敌
You don't come to be a casino owner without making enemies.
《教父》里的莫·格林不就如此
Look at Moe Greene in "The godfather."
这家伙似乎是个杰出市民
And this guy seems to be a stand-up citizen.
他有个基金会  专门捐钱给
He has a foundation that gives money to
慈善机构和公立学校
charities and public schools.
好  去查一下赌场员工
All right, check with the staff at the casino.
看看他是否在曼哈顿约了人
See if he had any meetings here in Manhattan
查清他离开大西洋城的时间
and find out what time he left Atlantic City.
好
All right.
如果有人约我
You know, if someone asked to meet me
夜深人静时去废弃仓库见面
at an abandoned warehouse in the dead of night,
我肯定不去
I'd pass.
这种场景我写过很多次了  绝没有好下场
I've written that scene enough times to know how it ends.
西格尔的导航仪上的那个地址
Hey, that address that was on Siegel's GPS?
是他前妻瑞贝卡的居住的大厦
Turns out it's a building where his ex-wife Rebecca lives.
他们离婚多久了
How long have they been divorced?
约六个月
About six months.
时间不久  可能心里还有不快
Recent enough for there to still be hard feelings.
根据邻居所述  那是相当不快
Mm. Well, according to the neighbors, very hard feelings.
昨晚有人报警投诉他们争吵声音太响
There was a report of a loud argument last night,
而且邻居说他们看见西格尔离开她家
and neighbors said they saw Siegel leaving her place
时间在八点半出头
just after 8:30.
刚好就在他遇害前
That's just before he was killed.
对  我们是吵架了  但我没杀他
Yeah, we argued, but I didn't kill him.
你们离婚后他经常来看你吗
Was it normal for him to come and see you after the divorce?
不是
No.
实际上我有几个月没见他了
In fact, I hadn't seen him in months.
我们现在关系不太好
We don't really get along anymore.
你们当时为什么起争执
What were the two of you fighting about?
西格尔太太
Ms. Siegel?
他说他惹麻烦了
He said he was in trouble.
什么样的麻烦
What kind of trouble?
他不肯说
He wouldn't say,
可他想让我签字转让一处投资性房产
but he wanted me to sign over an investment property
目前仍在我们两个人名下
that was still in both of our names--
是皇后区的一栋楼
a building here in queens,
只是一家店面和几间公寓
just a store and some apartments.
我不知道原因  可...
I don't know why, but...
他非常着急要我签字
he was very worked up about it.
他出价一百五十万买我那份
He offered me $1.5 million for my share,
都够买下整栋楼了
which is as much as the whole place was worth.
他说他要保命就指望它了
He said his life depended on it.
那么这栋楼...
So this building...
他出了全价一百五十万而不是半价
He offered you full price of $1.5 million instead of half,
而你依然拒绝了
and you still said no?
我当时不知内情  还以为他有什么阴谋
I didn't know. I thought he was working an angle.
我告诉他  没有律师在场  我是不会签的
I told him I couldn't sign anything without my lawyer.
然后萨姆昨晚离开你家后
And after Sam left your place last night,
你干什么了
what'd you did?
我后来整晚都待在家里
I was in my apartment for the rest of the evening.
门卫也证实了她的口供
So the doorman confirms the ex-wife's story.
她整晚都待在公寓里
She was in her apartment all night.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett,
我刚接到大西洋城市长的电话
I just received a call from the mayor of Atlantic City.
西格尔先生的死登上了头版新闻
Mr. Siegel's death is front-page news.
他们在打听嫌犯的消息
They're asking about suspects.
是  长官  我们也在查
Yes, sir. So are we.
他让前妻签字转让给他的房产查得怎么样了
Well, how about the property he asked his ex to sign over to him?
有进展吗
Anything on that?
只查到死者是一年半前购买的
Um, just that the victim purchased it a year and a half ago
全额现金付款
and paid cash for the full amount.
对  房产经纪人还觉得挺吃惊呢
Yeah, the real estate agent was surprised anyone bought it.
这栋房产已经挂牌销售有段时间了
It had been on the market for... quite a while.
我刚和萨姆·西格尔的办公室通过电话
Just got off the phone with Sam Siegel's office.
看来他昨晚不是一个人离开大西洋城
Apparently, he didn't leave Atlantic City alone last night.
没有迹象表明他的车上有乘客
There was no indication of a passenger in his car.
不是个乘客
Not a passenger.
是个司机
A driver.
六点半左右  萨姆一位常用司机拉夫·马里诺
Around 6:30, one of Sam's regular drivers, Ralph Marino,
去赌场门口接他
picked him up in front of the casino
然后驾车送他去纽约城
and drove him to New York city.
他现在在哪里
And where is he now?
没人知道  他今天没来上班
No one knows. He didn't show up for work today.
他要么被人灭口扔到河里
Which means he's either floating in the Hudson...
要么他也有瓜葛
or he's involved.
对马里诺先生有什么了解
Well, what do we know about Mr. Marino?
不是什么好人  那是肯定的
Well, he's no boy scout, that's for sure.
背景调查发现他曾被控恶性诈骗
Background check shows felony racketeering
和人身侵犯
and assault charges.
对拉夫·马里诺进行全面通缉
Put out an all points on Ralph Marino.
我让大西洋城的同事也去下通缉令
I'll have our brethren in Atlantic City do the same.
你们几个去大西洋城西格尔的赌场
You boys head down to Atlantic City to Siegel's casino.
去找马里诺的朋友和同事问话
Talk to Marino's friends and coworkers
看他们能不能提供他的下落
and see if any of them can shine some light on his whereabouts.
与此同时  贝克特
Meanwhile, Beckett,
你在这里指挥  让巡警去搜寻马里诺
you run point from here, get unis canvassing for Marino,
查明西格尔为何如此迫切要得到
and figure out why in the hell Siegel was so desperate
皇后区那一处房产
to get control over that property in queens.
遵命  长官  走吧  卡塞尔
Yes, sir. Come on, Castle.
盖茨警监说
Oh, uh, Captain Gates said
我们几个去大西洋城
the boys are going to Atlantic City.
对  我觉得她没说让你去
Yeah, I don't think she meant you.
实际上  是我说了算
Actually, that's my call.
你也一起去
You're with them.
另外  探长
Besides, detective,
没有他在  你的表现我拭目以待
I'm looking forward to seeing what you can do without him.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你觉得呢
What does it look like?
你们以为我会错过
Did you think I was gonna pass up
去大西洋帝国公路之旅吗
a road trip to the Boardwalk Empire,
去东海岸的舞蹈  赌博  舞女的罪恶之都
the east coast epicenter of dancing, gambling, showgirls, and sin?
你知道我们是去那儿调查凶案的吧
You do realize, we're going there to investigate a murder,
对吧
don't you?
先生们  如果人生教了我什么道理
Gentlemen, if I have learned one thing,
那就是不要让凶案这种小事
it's to not let a little thing like murder
坏了我们玩乐的兴致
get in the way of having a good time.
对了  我要副驾位子
And also, shotgun.
阿丽克西斯  我希望你没接电话
Hey, Alexis. I hope you're not answering
是因为你正忙着筹划你的女孩之夜
because you are busy planning your girls' night.
不管怎样  我要出城调查一桩案子
Anyway, I'm going out of town on a case,
今晚可能不回来了
and we may just be spending the night.
对  所以我会打电话抽查
Yeah. So I'll call and I'll check on you.
爱你  再见
Love you. Bye.
别逗了  卡塞尔  我们今晚不过夜
Come on, Castle. We are not spending the night.
你怎能这么说
How can you say that?
或许拉夫·马里诺很难找
And maybe Ralph Marino will be very difficult to find,
而且我觉得我们该从赌桌上开始找
and I think we should start looking at the craps tables.
-没错  -我有点理解为什么你要丢下贝克特了
- Yeah. - Oh, I'm starting to understand why you ditched Beckett.
我要声明  这辆车里唯一一个
A-and for the record, the one guy in this car
不是真正的警察  不许抢副驾位
who's not a real cop is not allowed to call shotgun.
公平竞争  先叫先得
Called it fair and square.
也许卡塞尔说得对
Maybe Castle's right.
反正我们也要去
I mean, if--since we're gonna be there,
何不考察一下宝石蓝适不适合
we might as well consider the Sapphire
举办单身派对呢
as a potential bachelor party venue.
我很高兴你这么说
I'm so happy you said that,
因为那里有好几个地方
because there are a number of establishments down there
可以举办单身派对
that cater to bachelor party events.
我想我们应该体验一下
I think maybe we should take a little sampling.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我们不去体验这些俱乐部
We are not sampling any clubs.
什么
What?
别这样  老兄  你干嘛要给我们泼冷水呢
Come on, bro. Why are you stalling us on this?
哈维尔  我
Look, Javier, I-I...
我有个坏消息
I got some bad news.
我必须得请珍妮同父异母的弟弟尼尔森
I had to ask Jenny's half-brother Nelson
做我的伴郎
to be my best man.
尼尔森
Nelson?
我在你生日会上见过的那个家伙
That guy I met at your birthday party?
才16岁  带牙套
16, with braces,
喋喋不休说要参加数学竞赛的那个家伙
couldn't stop talking about being a mathlete.
得照顾家里情绪  我别无选择
It was a family thing. I-I didn't have a choice.
你当然可以选
Yeah, you did.
不  其实在婚礼的问题上
No, actually, when it comes to weddings,
你确实没得选  相信我
uh, you don't. Trust me.
你可不想一结婚就让亲家结仇
You do not want to start a marriage with a family feud.
-糟透了  -我知道
- This sucks. - I know.
兄弟  我本想给你来个潇洒的送别
And I was gonna give you an awesome send-off, bro.
我知道
I know.
兄弟们  抱歉
Well, boys, I'm sorry.
很抱歉事情到了这般田地
I'm sorry it had to come to this.
我也不想的  但我们似乎别无选择
I didn't want it to, but it looks like we have no choice.
别无他法了
There is no other way.
只好明修栈道  暗度陈仓
I.B.P.W.O.C.
利用查案之机来一个即兴的单身派对了
Impromptu bachelor party while on case.
嗅到了吗
Ah, you smell that?
那是希望
That is the smell of hopes,
梦想和无尽机遇的气息
dreams, and endless opportunities.
别跟烟味
Not to be confused with cigarette smoke,
酒味和绝望的气息混淆了
day drinking, and desperation.
这就是赌场的绝妙之处
Well, that's the great thing about casinos--
没有时钟  没有窗户  也没人管你
No clocks, no windows, and no judgments.
好啊  美眉
How you doin'?
也许我们该在这儿过夜
Maybe we should stay the night.
怎么了
What?
莱恩警探  纽约警局
Detective Ryan, NYPD.
我来调查西格尔先生的死因
I'm here to investigate Mr. Siegel's death.
礼宾员在那边
The concierge is right over there.
娜蒂
Nadine.
先生们  欢迎来到宝石蓝
Gentlemen, welcome to the Sapphire.
我是娜蒂  私人礼宾员
I'm Nadine, the personal concierge.
得知萨姆的死讯  我们都悲痛欲绝
We're all devastated to learn about Sam.
我们想见见萨姆的合伙人  查理·特纳
We're supposed to meet Sam's business partner--- Charlie Turner.
我们要跟他谈谈你们一位员工
We need to talk to him about one of your employees.
他吩咐我带你们去见他  跟我来
He asked me to escort you to his table. Follow me.
如果你们想了解这家酒店的其他信息
And if you have any other questions about the hotel,
请随便问
don't hesitate to ask.
事实上  既然你提到了
Uh, actually, now that you mention it,
我很好奇  谁在主台上演出
I'm curious, who's playing on the main stage?
万一我们有时间去看演出呢
Just in case we have time to squeeze in a show.
我们本周末
Well, we're hosting
要举办猫王模仿秀大赛
an Elvis impersonators convention this weekend,
所以只请了胡萝卜头表演
so we're only featuring Carrot Top.
胡萝卜头  自从他改头换面之后
Carrot Top? I haven't seen him perform
我还没看过他表演呢
since his crazy makeover.
演出也会焕然一新的
It'll be like a new show.
-如何  -目前还没查到马里诺的料
- Well? - Uh, no luck so far on Marino.
大西洋城警局说他不在公寓
A.C.P.D. said that he's not at his apartment,
搜寻也没有任何收获
nothing turned up on the canvass.
皇后区那栋楼查到什么吗
What about the building in Queens?
网上搜到的结果显示没有任何的抵押和起诉
Well, online search shows that there's no liens or lawsuits,
所以看起来似乎没有不妥
so there doesn't seem to be anything unusual about it.
继续查
Keep digging.
探长
Uh, look, Detective,
我知道你认为我把你留下来
I know you're probably thinking that I have you here
可能是种变相惩罚
as some kind of punishment.
你是个好警察  但我觉得你去掉些干扰
You're a good cop, but I think you can be better
还能做得更好
if you minimize the distractions.
痛失萨姆  真是让人伤心欲绝
Hell of a thing, losing Sam.
我们是联手创办了这家赌场
You know, he and I started out in this business together?
我们一砖一瓦把这里盖起来
We built this place from the ground up.
你知道萨姆为什么去纽约吗
Do you have any idea what Sam was doing in New York?
不应该啊  他讨厌那个地方
Wasn't like him. He hated the city.
汤米
Yo, Tommy.
欢迎回来
Good to see you back.
需要什么  尽管开口
Anything you need, let me know.
知道我急需什么吗
You know what I need?
转转运
I need my luck to change.
一定会的
I'm sure it will.
大客户  有的是钱
Big whale, lots of dough.
昨晚给萨姆开车的拉夫·马里诺呢
What about Sam's driver last night--Ralph Marino?
你对他有什么了解
What can you tell us about him?
没什么  他只给我开过几次车而已
Not much. He drove me a couple of times.
这是你们要的他的人事档案
Here's his personnel file, like you asked.
说实在的  在他们之间发生过那件事以后
Honestly, after what happened between them,
我不明白萨姆为什么还继续把他留在身边
I don't know why Sam kept him around.
发生过什么事
Well, what happened?
特纳先生  抱歉打断您一下
Mr. Turner, sorry to interrupt.
面部识别系统查出了一个记牌者
Facial recognition got a hit on a card counter.
六号桌  穿紫色衬衫的那个人
Table six, purple shirt.
先生们  给你们介绍一下
Gentlemen, I'd like you to meet
我的安保顾问丹尼尔·苏利文
my Security Tech Daniel Sullivan.
你们用来追查恐怖分子的软件
The same software you guys use to track terrorists,
我们用来揪出卑鄙的小偷
we use to track low-life thieves.
安保人员  六号桌
Security escort, table number six,
穿紫色条纹衬衫的家伙  是个记牌者
purple striped shirt-- guy's counting cards.
看来你手腕挺严啊
Looks like you run a tight ship.
人人都自以为能诈赌场的钱
Everybody thinks they can beat the house.
如果你不管得严一点  他们就明目张胆
If you don't lay down the law, they'll rob you blind.
你刚刚说拉夫和萨姆之间有过节
Well, you said something happened between Ralph and Sam.
是什么事
What was that?
大约一周前
About a week ago,
他们俩在吧台前打了起来
the two of them had a scuffle at the bar.
因为什么事  萨姆让一个舞者
About what? Sam asked this dancer to, uh...
给他"吹箫"
blow on his dice.
结果呢  她是拉夫的妞儿
Turns out, she was Ralph's girl.
对啊  萨姆总是喜欢拈花惹草
Yeah, Sam was always a ladies' man,
而且其中很多还名花有主
and a lot of those ladies were already spoken for.
貌似他最近连连得手
It seems like he was on a little hot streak lately.
但运气就是这样
But that's the thing about luck, huh?
我赢了
I won!
它会变化
It changes.
非常感谢  特纳先生
Thank you very much, Mr. Turner.
我们在这逗留期间可能还会找你的员工问话
We may need to interview some of your staff while we're here.
请便
Of course.
需要帮忙找娜蒂就行了
Nadine can help you with whatever you need.
好的  谢谢
All right. Thanks.
伙计们
Guys...
拉夫把他的表兄列为紧急联系人
Ralph listed--as his emergency contact--his cousin.
你们猜这位表兄住在哪儿
Guess where he lives.
哪里
Where?
纽约  离案发现场不过八个街区
New York city. Eight blocks from our crime scene.
是拉夫绝佳的藏身之处
Great place for Ralph to hide out.
要出门吗  马里诺先生
Going somewhere, Mr. Marino?
不许动
Hold it.
举起手来  快点
Show us your hands, now.
我知道这看起来不妙
I know how it looks.
但我发誓  人不是我杀的
But I swear to god and my mother, I didn't kill him.
所以你裤子上别着把9毫米手枪
That's why you run away from me with 9-millimeter
一见我就跑
tucked in your pants,
是因为你是无辜的吗
'cause you're innocent?
得了吧  拉夫
Come on, Ralph.
我们知道你跟萨姆关系并不好
We know that you and Sam weren't on the best of terms.
我们两清了  我绝不会伤害他的
He and I were square. I would never hurt him.
我只是开车送他而已  他被杀时我并不在场
Look, all I did was drive him. I wasn't there when he was shot.
为什不在场  你不是他的司机吗
Why not? You were his driver.
那你做什么去了  半夜闲逛吗
So what did you do, go for a midnight stroll?
说起来确实如此
As a matter of fact, yeah.
见完他前妻后  他便让我送他去
A-after he spoke to his ex, he told me to take him out
城市另一头的一个废弃的仓库
to this abandoned warehouse on the other side of town.
他说要在那儿见一个人
He said there was someone he needed to meet.
而且要单独见面
He said he needed to meet him alone.
-见谁  -我也不知道
- Who? - Don't know.
萨姆给我了我五百块  让我自己想办法回去
Sam gave me 500 bucks, told me to find my own way home,
所以我就去我表兄家借宿
So I-I crashed at my cousin's place.
今早我在收音机上听到了发生的事情
And this morning, I-- I hear what happened on the radio.
我猜以我的案底  警察必然会找上我
I figured, with my record, folks would be looking at me.
你离开前有见到别的什么人吗
Did you see anybody else there before you left?
我离开时看到一辆黑色SUV开过来
Black S.U.V. drove up to the dock just as I was leaving,
但是没有看清车里的人
but I didn't see who was inside.
弹道科在给你的枪做对比
Ballistics is checking your 9.
你最好祈祷结果不匹配
You better hope it's not a match.
你觉得是他吗
What do you think?
我认为他知道自己必受怀疑
I think he's not stupid enough to kill Sam,
就不会傻到去杀萨姆
knowing it'll just point right back at him.
那么萨姆坐车来到纽约
So Sam drove up to new york
想要从前妻手中拿到皇后区的地产
to secure the property in Queens from his ex-wife.
然后去到码头去见一个人
And then went to the docks to meet with someone.
听上去像是有人等着接收那座房子
Sounds like someone was expecting the property,
萨姆没能把房子交出来  他们便杀了他
and when Sam couldn't deliver, they killed him.
为什么呢  这座房子到底有何特别之处
Why? What's so special about that property?
女士们  真是多谢了
Ladies, thank you so much.
你们绝想不到  我一定会物尽其用的
You have no idea. These will not go to waste.
多谢  听着  听着
Thank you. All right. All right.
虽然颇费功夫  但我还是搞到手了
It was not easy, but I did it.
我拿到了三张前排的
I managed to get three front-row seats
赌场喜剧演出的票
to the burlesque show at the borgata,
还在X俱乐部预订了贵宾桌
Also reservations at a premium table
以及酒水服务
at the X club with bottle service.
-很不错嘛  -你们查到了什么
- Sweet. - What'd you guys come up with?
萨姆的助理完全不知道
Well, Sam's assistant didn't know anything
皇后区地产的事
about the property in Queens,
但是她提到昨天确实发生了点不寻常的事
But she did remember something odd about yesterday.
萨姆按他的常规晨间安排
Apparently, Sam followed his usual morning routine--
先在宾馆作了按摩
he had a massage in the hotel,
然后与赌场经理开会
then a meeting with his casino manager,
午餐后  他回来时唇角带血
Then after lunch, he came back with a bloody lip.
怎么弄成那样
How'd he get it?
萨姆闪烁其词  但是他的助理说
Well, Sam was evasive, but his assistant said,
看起来像是被人打得
it looked like someone hit him.
所以萨姆挨了一拳  而不久之后
So Sam gets punched, and soon after,
他匆忙赶到纽约
he rushes off to new york,
急切得想要回那处地产
frantically trying to get that property.
再然后就被枪杀了
Then he's shot dead.
这其中必然有联系
Well, it's gotta be connected.
问题是  我们并不知道这一拳是谁打的
The problem is, we don't know who threw that punch.
我想我知道怎么找出那个人
I think I know how we can find out.
你是说昨天下午两点钟吗
You said yesterday at 2:00 p.m.?
是的  没错
Yeah, that's correct.
面部识别软件需要一些时间
It'll take a second for facial recognition
把西格尔先生从监控录像带中找出来
to pick out Mr. Siegel in all the footage.
你们会把以前顾客的数据保留在系统里吗
Do you keep former guests in the system?
当然了  这样才能标记出有前科的赌徒
Sure do. That's how we flag gamblers with priors.
-我呢  -我看看  理查德·卡塞尔
- What about me? - Let's see. Richard... Castle.
居住地  纽约
Oh, resident, new york city...
2003年妨害社会治安  拒捕
Disorderly conduct, resisting arrest in 2003, and, uh,
看来上回你来宝石蓝
apparently last time you were at the Sapphire,
一个无心之失
you accidentally
把床垫点着了
set a mattress on fire,
而且当时窗帘上到处是果酱什么的
and the drapes were covered in jam.
是呀  那真是个美好的夜晚
Yeah. That was a fun night.
记录属实
Check.
找到他了
Ah, here he is.
那是西格尔先生
That's Mr. Siegel,
下午两点  出电梯
leaving the elevator at 2:00 p.M.
他嘴唇已经流血了  能倒回到之前吗
He already has a bloody lip. Can you back that up to earlier?
长官  现在方便吗
Sir, am I interrupting?
正在察看皇后区那栋楼的租客背景
Just running background on the tenants in the Queens building.
我想我大概知道为什么有人想要萨姆死
I-I think I might know why someone wanted Sam dead.
根据银行记录  昨天萨姆从宝石蓝的
According to his bank, Sam wired over $10 million
商业帐户电汇出超过一千万
out of the Sapphire's business account yesterday,
将其洗劫一空
wiping it clean.
一千万  他汇到哪里
$10 million? Wh-where did he transfer it to?
一个开曼群岛的离岸帐户
To an offshore account in the Caymans.
看他在这儿  在赌桌边
So here he is, parting ways with the pit boss
与赌场监管人告别
at one of the tables.
那会儿嘴唇还没破  请继续放吧
No bloody lip yet. Let it play, please.
还有其他角度的镜头拍到吗
Is there another angle on that?
那是查理·特纳  萨姆的生意伙伴
that's Charlie Turner, Sam's business partner.
为什么查理会打萨姆
Why would charlie attack sam?
我想我知道原因
I think I know.
刚才是贝克特的电话
That was beckett.
萨姆·西格尔在挪用赌场资金
Sam Siegel's been embezzling from the casino.
而且已经盗走了上千万
He's ripped 'em off for millions.
听上去萨姆想诈赌场的钱
Sounds like sam was trying to beat the house.
而查理则严惩不贷
And Charlie laid down the law.
查理  你是不是有什么事忘了交待
Something you forgot to tell us, Charlie?
生意伙伴也会有分歧
Business partners have disputes.
这不是大事
Doesn't mean anything.
那你们为什么起争执
What was it about?
关于新床单的品种有不同意见罢了
The thread count on the new sheets.
不是因为萨姆从赌场挪用的一千多万吗
Not the 10-plus million that Sam stole from the casino?
你知道他在挪用公款
You knew he was embezzling.
是的  我承认我知道  那又如何
Okay, yeah, I knew. So?
那就有一千万个理由杀了他
So it's 10 million motives for murder.
你们可能已经注意到了
You know, you may have noticed,
赌场里遍布了摄像头
we have a few cameras here at the casino.
你们大可以查看一下
Take a look.
我一直在这  而非在纽约谋杀我的合作伙伴
I was here, not in New York, killing my partner.
是吗
Really?
我觉得这一记右勾拳看上去像是个警告
'Cause that right hook kinda looks like a warning to me.
你知道吗  在这座城市里
Yeah, you know, this town...
不小心点  就会毁了自己
If you're not careful, it corrupts your soul.
萨姆和我已经是20年的搭档了
Sam and I were partners 20 years,
即便如此  他就觉得可以偷我的钱了吗
and still, he thinks it's okay to steal from me?
我发现他转出了一千万美金后
When I saw he'd transferred the $10 million out,
就去赌场找到了他
I found him on the casino floor,
结果他说他根本不知此事
and he denied even knowing about it.
换你你信吗  所以我给了他一拳
Can you believe it? So I punched him,
并告诉他  不管是不是朋友
and I told him, friend or no friend,
他都最好把钱赶紧打回我账户
he better have that money back in my account,
否则就让他一辈子不能走路
or he'd never walk again.
我一定是吓到他了
So I must have scared him,
因为几小时后我接到电话  他说
because I get a call a few hours later, and he said
他会在今天把钱打到我账户
he'd have the money back in my account today.
到了今天
And now it's today.
我朋友死了  钱还是不见踪影
And my friend is dead, and the money's still gone.
他们查看了监控录像
So the boys checked security footage,
他们说查理一整晚都在赌场
and they said that Charlie was on the casino floor the whole night.
他也许雇了别人
He could've paid someone.
可能吧  但是为什么他还没拿到钱
Yeah, but why would he kill Sam
就杀了萨姆呢
before he got his money?
如果萨姆真的偷了
And if Sam actually stole something,
为什么不坐飞机逃去巴巴多斯岛
why wasn't he on a plane to Barbados?
为什么还要浪费时间来纽约
Why was he wasting his time coming up to New York?
而这一切又和皇后区的房产有何联系呢
And how is all this connected to the property in Queens?
我觉得我们还少些什么
I think we're missing something.
还缺少一些能够让萨姆看起来
There's some piece of the puzzle that'll help make
毫无规律的行为解释得通的线索
all of Sam's seemingly random actions make sense.
实际上  这种事
Actually, that's something
是卡塞尔最拿手的
that Castle's pretty good at,
看着已有的线索
taking a look at what we have
然后找出缺少的那一块
and then helping to find that piece.
卡塞尔先生喜欢
Mr. Castle likes to throw
丢出一大堆疯狂的理论
a whole lot of crazy theories against the wall.
真正的警探可没有那闲工夫
Real detectives don't have that luxury.
我们的工作是关注于事实
It's our job to look at the facts.
银行记录显示萨姆早上9点47分取走了钱
The bank report indicates that Sam moved the money at 9:47 a.m.
通过他们的网站上的电子转账
Via electronic transfer on their web site.
如果我们能查出在此之前萨姆
Now if we can find out who Sam talked to
和谁交谈过或见过面
or met with right before that,
也许就能搞清楚到底发生了什么
we could maybe figure out what's going on.
-9点47吗  -对
- 9:47? - Yes.
萨姆的助手给他安排了
Sam's assistant has him...
全身按摩
at a massage.
对  西格尔先生昨天9点做了一小时的按摩
Yeah, Mr. Siegel had an hour session yesterday at 9:00.
怎么了
Why?
我们想要知道萨姆在按摩的时候
Well, we need to know if Sam made
有没有接打电话或者有没有
or received any phone calls or perhaps any visitors
来访者
during his session.
没有  他很专注地享受按摩
No. He was very focused on the service.
安玻  我们知道他9点47分上网了
Amber, we know he went online at 9:47.
我们只想知道他在此前后有没有
We just need to know if he made contact with anybody
和其他人接触
right before or right after.
我说了  他既没上网也没打电话
I told you, he wasn't on the phone and he wasn't online.
现在的移动设备小巧玲珑
Well, what with mobile devices being so small and slim,
也许他就抓在手上
perhaps he had it in his hand.
他的手  有其他事要忙
His hands were otherwise occupied.
明白了
Oh. Oh. I get it.
是那种按摩啊
That--that kind of massage.
那么萨姆没有转账
So then Sam didn't make the transfer.
他没有偷钱  有人从他那里偷钱了
He didn't steal the money. Somebody stole it from him.
安玻  我们想知道是否
Uh, Amber, we need to know if, um,
也许有什么
perhaps there was anything, uh,
也许  预约的时候有什么不寻常的
maybe, unusual about the appointment.
唯一奇怪的事情是
The only thing that seemed odd was that
那天早上是娜蒂打电话来确定预约
Nadine called that morning to confirm the appointment.
娜蒂  那个私人礼宾员吗
Nadine-- the personal concierge?
那有什么不寻常的
Why was that unusual?
通常是西格尔先生的助手来预订
Mr. Siegel's assistant usually books the appointment.
这是第一次娜蒂打电话来
This was the first time Nadine ever called.
等下
Wait a minute.
你说她的名字是娜蒂·埃斯皮诺萨吗
Did you say her name was Nadine Espinoza?
对  礼宾员  你熟悉这个名字吗
Yeah, the concierge. That name mean anything to you?
埃斯皮诺萨
Uh, Espinoza
是萨姆在皇后区房产的
is the last name of one of the tenants
某个住户的姓氏
in Sam's building in Queens-- uh...
特瑞莎和胡安
Teresa and Juan.
他们在一楼开杂货店
They run the bodega on the ground floor,
他们的女儿名字就是娜蒂
and they have a daughter named Nadine.
这就是联系
That's our connection.
莱恩  带她回局里
Ryan, bring her in.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
娜蒂的主管说她十分钟前
Nadine's supervisor said she left her office
离开了办公室  说她病了要回家
ten minutes ago, claimed she needed to go home sick.
-我们还有机会在外面抓住她  -走吧
- Well, there's a chance we can catch her outside. - Let's go.
她在那
There she is.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
不  不  救命啊
No! No! Help!
我们今晚看不了胡萝卜头喜剧表演了是吗
We're not gonna be seeing Carrot Top tonight, are we?
是啊  亲爱的  看来
Yeah, so, honey, it turns out
今晚我都得耗在这里了
I am going to be stuck here for the rest of the night.
一切顺利吧
well, is everything all right?
是的是的  只是
Yeah, yeah, just--
案子变得有点复杂
The case just got a little complicated.
不过我希望你今晚和你的闺蜜们
But I want you to have a great time tonight
玩得开心
with your girlfriends.
我会的  你要保证安安全全的
I will, if you promise to be safe.
好的  爱你
Deal. Love you.
爱你
Love you, too.
嗨  茱尔斯  进来吧
Hey, Jules. Come on in.
我带来了最爱的"分手快乐"零食
I've got my fave "Get over a breakup" snack,
当然还有超赞的爱情喜剧电影《伴娘》
and a kick-ass chick flick-- "Bridesmaids," of course.
好的  她们正在路上
Okay. Uh, the girls are on their way,
而且凑巧的是  我爸爸出城了
and it turns out, my dad's out of town,
所以家里只有我们了
so we have the whole place to ourselves.
酷
Cool.
对了  米娜说她男朋友可能顺路来
By the way, Mena said her boyfriend might swing by
给她送件外套
and drop off her jacket.
他是不是跟布莱恩是朋友
Isn't he friends with Brian from homeroom?
帅到爆的那个布莱恩吗  没错
Hot-as-hell Brian? Yeah.
他们要去电影院过兄弟之夜
I think they're doing a bros' night at the movies.
也许我们可以把他们也邀请过来
Well, maybe we could invite them over, too,
一起在这儿看电影
all watch a movie here.
-布莱恩  -对
- Brian? - Yeah.
他是体优生唉
He's, like, a total jock.
跟你喜欢的型完全相反
Completely the opposite of your type.
我知道
I know.
他非常  不像阿什利
He's so... not Ashley.
我来给米娜发信息
I'll text Mena.
贝克特说SUV的车牌是偷来的
So Beckett says the plates on the SUV came back as stolen.
很有可能是在萨姆被杀的
Most likely the same SUV that was spotted
那个废弃仓库被人看到开出来的那辆
coming out of that abandoned warehouse where Sam was killed.
如果是同一辆车  他们为什么要抓娜蒂
If it's the same car, why would they want Nadine?
因为不管怎么回事  娜蒂定是参与其中
Because whatever this is, Nadine is knee-deep in it.
是深陷其中
Try neck-deep.
大西洋城警察让我检查了
A.C.P.D. let me check into
娜蒂工作包里的笔记本电脑
that laptop in Nadine's work bag.
我看了她的浏览器历史记录
I checked her browser history.
猜猜谁在昨天早上9点47分
Guess who paid a visit to the New Reserve Bank website
登陆了新储银行的网站
yesterday at 9:47 a.m.?
娜蒂是我们要找的贼吗
Nadine's our thief?
是的  礼宾员干了一大票啊
Yep, our concierge pulled quite a score.
她用萨姆的帐号登陆
She logged in with Sam's account information
转了一千万
and transferred the 10 mil.
劫走她的人是为了要钱
So whoever took her is after the money.
他们本想跟萨姆要  没拿到
They tried to get it from Sam. When that didn't work,
就杀了他  现在又盯上了娜蒂
they killed him, and now they've gone for Nadine.
但还是不知道"他们"是谁
Okay, but we still don't know who "they" are.
能让一切都说得通的只有一个人
There's only one person who makes any sense.
这笔钱的主人
The guy whose money it is.
我为什么要绑架自己赌场的礼宾员
Why would I kidnap my own concierge?
因为你发现是她偷了你的钱
Because you found out she was the one who stole your money.
娜蒂偷了我的钱
Nadine stole my money?
不要再装了  我们知道你已经发现了
You can stop the theatrics. We know you know.
特纳先生
Mr. Turner,
你的赌场有很多辆黑色SUV
your casino maintains a fleet of black SUVs
来接送你的贵宾
to shuttle around your high-rollers.
所有赌场都有  这证明不了什么
All the casinos do. That doesn't prove anything.
那你肯定不介意让我们检查一下
Well, then you won't mind if we inspect them.
确认每辆车都没有嫌疑
Just to make sure they're all accounted for.
到此为止了
We're done here.
什么意思
Excuse me?
你们从另一个州过来
You people are here from another state.
在这里没有管辖权  也没有搜查令
You have no jurisdiction and you have no warrant,
我想我对你们已经忍无可忍了
and I believe I've tolerated your presence long enough.
滚出我的赌场
Get out of my casino.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我像是在开玩笑吗
Do I look like I'm kidding?
给我立刻离开
I want you to leave now.
他能这么做吗
Can he do that?
什么  你们怎么被赶出来了
What? How did you guys get kicked out?
查理宣称要全力配合
Turns out Charlie's version
到头来也是有所保留的
of full cooperation isn't all that full.
他赶我们出来
The only reason he kicked us out
是因为他才是幕后黑手
is because he's behind the whole thing.
但在他的赌场门口进行绑架
Yeah, but kidnap somebody right in front of his casino?
也太胆大妄为了
That's a bit bold.
如果他知道是她  他干嘛等这么久
If he knew it was her, why would he wait?
为何不在她当班的时候
Why didn't he just grab her in the casino
在赌场里截住她
while she was on shift?
有道理  我们说偷钱的人是娜蒂时
Yeah, I mean, he did seem genuinely surprised
他确实挺吃惊的
when we told him it was Nadine.
说不定他并不知晓
Maybe he didn't know.
但他是唯一有动机的人
Yeah, but he's the only one with motive.
也不一定啊
Well, not necessarily.
如果有其他人知道是娜蒂干的
What if someone else knew what Nadine did
并想得到这笔钱呢
and wanted the money?
那他们怎么发现的呢
How would they find out?
说不定是娜蒂说的
Maybe Nadine told 'em.
这就能解释电话记录了
I mean, that would explain the phone records.
怎么说
How so?
听着  我调出了她的电话记录
Listen, I pulled her phone history.
她在9点47分转账前后打了两通电话
She called a number inside the casino immediately before
给一个赌场内部号码
and after making that transfer at 9:47.
通过分机号码查到是一个叫丹尼尔·苏利文的人
I tracked down the extension to a-a Daniel Sullivan.
丹尼尔吗  是查理的安保人员
Daniel? That's Charlie's security guy.
这就能解释
That would explain
娜蒂是怎么拿到萨姆的密码的
how Nadine got ahold of Sam's passwords.
丹尼尔是她的同伙
Daniel is her partner.
他能监视赌场的每一个角落
He's got eyes and ears all over that casino.
好的  去问他话
All right. See what he knows.
没法问啊
We can't.
他在赌场里
He's inside the casino,
保安不会让我们再进去的
And their security won't let us back in.
按兵不动  我这就过去
Okay, sit tight. I'm driving down.
不  不用  贝克特  你不用过来
No, no, no. Beckett, you don't have to do that.
-不用  我们...  -我们能行
- No, no, we got - We really have-- we got it.
她挂电话了
Yeah, she's gone.
我跟教练说  如果我在3号位无人盯防
So I told coach, if I'm open on the 3,
控球后卫最好传球给我
the point guard better feed me.
真的很有趣
That's really interesting.
但有必要把半支球队的人都请来吗
But did you have to invite half the team over?
我喜欢你的头发  它是...
I like your hair. It's...
红色的
red.
失陪
Will you excuse me for a sec?
我得跟你谈谈
Hey, I need to talk to you.
不能等等吗  有人把搅拌机弄坏了
Can it wait a second? I think someone just broke the blender.
这些人都是谁啊
Who are all these people?
杰米·克鲁斯刚在脸谱网上更新了状态
Jamie Cruz just posted an update on Facebook
说你家开派对
that you're having a party.
-什么  -不过他是个衰仔
- What? - He's kind of a loser, though,
我估计他没什么朋友
so I'm--I'm sure he doesn't have that many friends.
是啊  闲在家里等着有人开派对的人
Yeah. I mean, how many people are just sitting at home
又有多少呢
waiting to hear about a party?
这是史上办案时最烂的即兴单身派对
This is the worst impromptu bachelor party while on case ever.
这太丢人了
This is humiliating.
我们可是纽约警局的凶案组警探
We're homicide detectives with the NYPD.
不幸的是  我们在新泽西
Unfortunately, we're in New Jersey.
但至少眼下没什么急事
At least we're not on a ticking clock
虽然有个女人被绑架了
because a woman's been kidnapped.
等等  刻不容缓啊
Oh, wait. We are.
总归有办法能让我们进去吧
There's gotta be some other way we can get in.
如果我告诉你们  我有办法
What if I told you, I could get us back in the hotel,
避过面部识别
past security, all...
通过保安  重新打入赌场内部呢
while circumventing facial recognition?
怎么才能做到呢
How the hell are you gonna do that?
够帅气
Very nice.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
你怎么知道她不是对我说的
How do you know she wasn't talking to me?
怎么  棕色皮肤当不了猫王吗
What, Elvis can't be brown?
我是拉丁版猫王
I'm Elvez.
嗨  你好吗
Hey. How you doin'?
搞什么飞机
What the hell?
我们想跟你谈谈娜蒂
We'd like a word about Nadine.
你在开玩笑吧
You're joking, right?
我像是在开玩笑吗
Does it look like we're joking?
好吧  你们干嘛穿成这样
Okay. Why are you guys dressed like that?
更重要的问题是
A better question is,
娜蒂为何在昨天9点48分打电话给你
why did Nadine call you at 9:48 yesterday?
被你们发现了
You know about that?
我们知道你们是同伙
We know you two were partners.
谁劫走了她
Who took her?
SUV里的人是谁
Who was in the SUV?
我不知道
I don't know.
事情不该发展成这样的
I... this wasn't supposed to happen.
你是在说  你只是碰巧
Are you guys saying that you accidentally stole
从查理和萨姆那偷了一千万吗
$10 million from Charlie and Sam?
没有  我们不想偷钱
No, we didn't steal it.
我们只想用钱作筹码
We were--we were using it as leverage.
让萨姆交出皇后区她父母住的那栋楼
To get Sam to hand over that building in Queens for her parents.
没错  但原因跟你们想的不一样
Yeah, but it-- it's not why you think.
几个月前  娜蒂和我开始约会
Nadine and I started dating a few months ago.
我们相爱了
We're in love.
我们想移居别处开始新生活
We wanted to start over, move somewhere,
可萨姆不肯让她走
but Sam wouldn't let her go.
他们是一对吗
They were an item?
不  是他一厢情愿
No, only in his mind.
她拒绝了他给的所有好处  可他不肯罢手
She refused all of his advances, but he wouldn't stop.
她为什么不举报他
Why didn't she report him?
因为这是他的赌场
Because this was his casino.
没人会把她的话当回事
Nobody would've taken her seriously.
她一年前试图辞职
She tried to quit about a year ago.
他就买下她父母住的那栋楼
That's when he bought her parents' building
并威胁说如果她不跟他上床
and threatened to evict 'em
就把她父母赶出去
if she didn't sleep with him.
我必须想办法阻止他
I had to do something to stop him.
所以你想到扣下这笔钱
So you came up with a plan to hold the money hostage
直到他交出房子的契约
until he turned over the deed?
他本来是要签放弃产权的合约
He was gonna sign it over as a quitclaim,
然后我会把钱转回来
and then I was gonna transfer the money back.
到时候娜蒂就自由了
And then Nadine would be free.
可这也解释不了谁杀了萨姆
None of this explains who killed Sam.
这笔钱让萨姆惊慌失措
Something about the money made Sam panic.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
当我打电话给萨姆
When I called Sam to give him
让他按我的指示解除契约
instructions about the deed,
他告诉我  我偷错了钱
he told me, I stole the wrong person's money.
他告诉我如果被他们发现  我们都死定了
And he told me, when they found out, we'd all be dead.
他指的是谁
Who was he talking about?
我不知道
I don't know.
嗨  各位
Oh, hey, guys.
我们正要离开
Uh, we were just leaving.
这里不是舞厅啊
This isn't the ballroom. Huh.
我来猜猜  脸谱网上获悉的
Let me guess. Facebook?
是推特  顺便说句  你还是把门开着吧
Twitter. You might want to just leave this open, by the way.
楼下还有一堆人
There's, like, a whole bunch of people
排队等着上电梯呢
lining up for the elevator downstairs.
小朱  这简直是场灾难
Julie, this is a disaster.
别紧张  开派对嘛
Chill. It's just a party.
你就好好找点乐子吧
Have some fun for once.
找乐子  这里一半的人我甚至都不认识
Fun? I don't even know half these people.
那么...
Oh, what about, um...
布莱恩呢
Uh, Brian?
他的智商堪比松鼠了
He has the I.Q. Of a squirrel.
天啊  我爸爸会杀了我的
Oh, god. My dad's gonna kill me.
拜托  你有这世上最酷的爸爸
Please. You have the coolest dad ever.
他要是现在走进来  我打赌他也不会介意的
If he were to walk in right now, I bet he wouldn't care.
你说得对  他可能不会介意
You're right. He probably wouldn't care.
问题是  我介意
The problem is, I do.
各位  听好了
Everybody, listen up.
派对结束了
The party is over.
感谢光临  感谢把饮料洒得到处都是
Thanks for coming, thanks for spilling,
感谢把全世界活着的青少年都叫来了
Thanks for telling every teenager with a pulse.
现在  所有人  请出去
Now, everybody, out.
不是吧  没搞错吧
Oh, really? Really?
要不是扁你犯法  我扁死你
If it wasn't illegal, I'd kick your ass.
他们把卡塞尔带哪儿去了
Wonder where they took Castle.
我警告过你再进赌场
You were told what would happen
会有什么下场
if you came back here.
可我也没蠢到殴打警察
Now I'm not stupid enough to beat on cops,
但是相反地  你就不同了
but you, on the other hand, are a different story.
我要我的钱  卡塞尔先生
I want my money, Mr. Castle,
你最好把你知道的一切都告诉我
So you better tell me everything you know.
我知道那不是你的钱
I know it's not your money.
让我们单独聊会儿
Would you excuse us?
谁告诉你的
Who told you?
没人告诉我
No one told me.
我想明白了
I put the pieces together.
萨姆被杀  娜蒂被绑架
Sam's murder, Nadine's kidnapping,
如果是你的钱  这一切根本说不通
None of it makes any sense if it was your money.
你知道我怎么想吗
You know what I think?
我想娜蒂从你那儿偷的钱
I think the money Nadine stole from you
其实另有所属
actually belonged to someone else.
否则你也不会如此绝望
Otherwise, you wouldn't be so desperate.
告诉我  查理  发生了什么
So tell me, Charlie, what happened,
你和萨姆从一家不允许弹性还款的机构
you and Sam take out a loan from an institution
借了一大笔钱吗
that doesn't offer flexible payment plans?
你们从黑帮手里借了钱
You borrowed money from the mob.
所以你才不想我们四处查探
That's why you didn't want us sniffing around here.
我想不明白的是  你怎么会这么蠢
What I can't figure out is, how could you be so stupid?
银行不肯放贷款
The banks weren't lending.
我们需要现金注入  否则就得关门
We needed a cash infusion, or else we would've had to fold.
现在钱没了
And now the money's gone.
你知不知道欠黑帮的钱
You have any idea how bad it is
逾期不还  后果有多严重
to default on a loan from the mob?
他们怎么查到娜蒂的
How'd they find out about Nadine?
我怎么知道
Hell if I know.
也许是萨姆告诉他们的
Maybe Sam told 'em.
我只知道
All I know...
我急需找回我的钱
is that I need my money back.
我可以替你把钱找回来
I can get your money back for you.
但我需要你为我做点事
But I need you to do something for me.
那些人是谁
Who are they?
不  没门
No. No way.
拜托  查理
Come on, Charlie.
他们杀了萨姆
They killed sam.
找不回他们那笔钱
And unless they get their money back,
他们会杀了娜蒂
they're gonna kill Nadine
接着就轮到你
And then you.
这就是你手上的牌
Those are your cards.
你真的打算这么打吗
Is this really how you're gonna play 'em?
很好笑哈
Um... Funny story?
我们  是这样...
We, uh, look, this is...
我们可以解释
We can explain.
不用  我都不确定我想知道
No, I'm not even sure I want to know.
是卡塞尔的主意
It was Castle's idea.
而且很奏效
And it worked.
我知道谁杀了萨姆
I know who killed Sam.
谁
Who?
汤米·莫莱蒂
Tommy Moretti.
他六个月前借了一笔高利贷给宝石蓝赌场
He made a hard-money loan to the Sapphire six months ago,
现在到期了
and it's due.
娜蒂偷的是他的钱
It was his money that Nadine stole.
袭击重罪  蓄意谋杀  敲诈
Felony assault, attempted murder, racketeering--
联调局多年来一直想抓到他的把柄
The feds have been trying to get him for years.
他今天早上还在酒吧
He was at the bar earlier today.
他告诉查理  他需要转转运
He told Charlie he needed his luck to change.
也许是个隐晦的威胁
probably a veiled threat.
他要是把她杀了怎么办
What if he kills her?
不会  他太想要回他的钱了
Nah, he wants his money too much.
按计划行事
Just stick to the plan.
查理打给了莫莱蒂
Charlie called Moretti,
让他明早银行一开门
told him to meet him at the casino,
就来赌场见他
first thing in the morning when the banks open.
你把一千万交出来
Once you turn over the $10 million,
他就会交出娜蒂
he'll turn over Nadine.
然后我们就以谋杀萨姆的罪名逮捕他
And then we'll arrest him for Sam's murder.
要是他发现这是个圈套呢
And what if he smells a trap?
他不会的  我们会有所准备
He won't. We'll be ready.
他来了
Here he comes.
汤米·莫莱蒂
Tommy Moretti.
这家伙是个反社会者
The guy is a sociopath.
问题是  半个城的人都靠他发薪水吃饭
The problem is, with half the city on his payroll,
没人敢碰他
no one can touch him.
胆子挺大呀  小鬼  敢偷我的钱
You got some pretty big balls, kid, to steal from me.
我非常抱歉  莫莱蒂先生
Look, I-I'm sorry, Mr. Moretti.
我完全不知道那笔钱是您的
I had no idea you were involved.
只要我见到娜蒂
I'll log on and transfer the funds
就马上把钱转还给您
as soon as I see Nadine.
你活着就够走运了  小子
You got a lot of demands for a kid
还敢跟我谈条件
who's lucky to be sucking down air right now.
你说过会放了她的
You said you'd let her go.
好戏现在才要上演呢
Okay, here's where it gets interesting.
真奇怪  我就觉得事情不会这么顺利
Funny. Somehow I figured I wasn't done.
坐吧  莫莱蒂先生
Take a seat, Mr. Moretti.
我们有些关于萨姆·西格尔谋杀案的问题要问
We got a few questions about Sam Siegel's murder.
探长  我今天刚好心情大好
You got me in a cooperative mood, detective.
我的钱拿到了  有什么能帮助你的吗
Now that I got my money back, what can I do for you?
萨姆被杀那晚
The night of Sam's murder,
你在卡麦餐厅点了一份晚餐
you charged a meal at Carmine's.
距离案发现场只有一英里远
That's about a mile away from the crime scene.
为了份芝士烤鸡  还真是穿山越岭呢
That's a long way to go for good chicken parm.
我当时就是特别想吃
I had a craving.
是指意大利美食
For good italian
还是萨姆从你那偷走的一千万美金
or for the $10 million Sam stole from you?
拜托  如果是我杀了萨姆
Come on. If I had killed Sam,
我会让你们找到尸体吗
you think you would've ever found the body?
我不是你们要找的人
The guy you're looking for ain't me.
但你的确在那里
But you were there.
萨姆打了电话给我
Sam called me.
他说还贷遇到点麻烦
He said he was having trouble repaying the loan.
所以我安排了一次面谈
So I arranged a meeting.
可不  刚好是在像你这样的人
Yeah, at just the kind of place
喜欢射杀别人的地方会面
guys like you like to put bullets into guys like him.
从死人手里要不到钱
You can't get money from a dead guy.
我得先断了他的腿  把赌场收了
I'd have broken his legs and taken his casino first.
我知道勒索的事
Now see, I knew all about the blackmail.
萨姆跟我说过
Sam told me.
他说我根本不用担心
He said I had nothing to worry about
他前妻已经把皇后区的那块地签给他了
because his ex-wife had signed over the property in Queens.
勒索的人已经把那一千万转回来了
The blackmailers were transferring the 10 mil back.
他本要在早上把钱给我
He was gonna drop off the money in the morning,
所以
so...
我多给了他一天的时间
I gave him an extra 24 hours.
那就是我最后一次见到他
It was the last I saw of him.
但萨姆撒了谎
Except Sam lied.
他前妻并没有把那块地给他
His ex-wife never signed.
不  她给了
Yeah, she did.
他把签名给我看了
He showed me the signature himself.
那就是我多给了他一天时间的原因
That's the reason I gave him the extra time.
我没有说谎
I didn't lie.
那么萨姆离开公寓以后
So then what happened to the paperwork
那份文件是怎么处理的
after Sam left your apartment?
他带走了
He took it with him.
那就奇怪了
That's odd.
我们本以为会在他的尸体上找到文件
I would've thought I would've found it on his body.
但并没有
But we didn't.
这让我很好奇它的下落
It made me wonder where it was.
也许是杀他的人拿走的
Maybe the person who killed him took it.
是啊  也许是她拿的
Yeah, maybe she did.
警员在你家的垃圾桶里
So uniforms found this
找到了这个
in your apartment's trash bin.
上面有你的签名
It has your signature on it.
你说谎了
You did lie.
他恳求我...
He pleaded with me...
求我
Begged me
签了那份文件
to sign that form.
当我说不要的时候
And when I said no,
他掏出枪  放在我的嘴里
he took out his gun, put it in my mouth,
跟我说  如果我不签
and told me, if I didn't sign the form,
他就要我脑浆四溅
he would paint the walls with my brains.
我之所以能跟他离婚
The only reason I was able to get that divorce
是因为他说我已是个半老徐娘
was because he said I had gotten old,
他不要我了
that he was done with me.
我非常感激
And I was grateful,
得以逃出他的魔掌
grateful for a way out.
可一旦和萨姆这样的男人扯上关系
But with a man like Sam...
怎么逃也逃不出
You're never really out.
因此当他说
So when he told me
有人想要他的命时
that someone wanted him dead,
我想  我的机会来了
I thought, here's my chance.
然后发生了什么事
So then what happened?
他用我的电话约了那次见面
He made a call from my phone about the meet.
他走以后
After he left,
我拿出那把点38
I took out the 38
结婚两周年时他送给我的枪
that he gave me for our second anniversary,
从员工通道跟出去
went out the service exit.
像野兽一般猎杀了野兽一般的他
And I hunted him down like the vicious animal he was.
我已经请地检官
I've asked the D.A.
考虑减轻罪行了
to look into the mitigating circumstances.
他们给她认罪协议的时候
They'll take her situation
会把她的情况列入考虑范围
into account when they offer her a plea.
这案子感谢你的帮忙
Thank you for your help on this one.
偶尔从警探的角度办案
I enjoy checking out the view from the trenches
也不赖
once in a while.
有好的团队总是事半功倍
Yeah, well, it helps to be surrounded by a good team.
你是指卡塞尔
You mean Castle.
是你说的  不是我
You said it, not me.
他不是警察
He's not a cop.
所以他才如此地出色
Yeah, but that's what makes him so good.
说到他们
Well, speaking of which,
他们人呢
Uh, where are they?
我放了他们一下午假
I gave them the afternoon off.
碍于莱恩的那位未成年伴郎
Apparently, Ryan got stuck with an underage best man,
伙计们打算给他先办个非正式单身派对
so the boys are giving him the nunofficial bachelor party.
我相信你会把
I trust you'll edit
他们的报告也写出来
their side of the investigation in the report.
你这是怎么了
What happened to you?
没怎么
Nothing.
没事  但这儿是怎么了
Nothing. What-- what happened here?
没怎么
Nothing.
那个...
Where's the, um...
那个银质犬像哪去了
Where's the little silver dog statue
沙发后面那个
That's usually on the back of the couch?
奶奶说需要它
Oh, I think Gram said she needed it
做舞台布景
for set dressing for her play.